let's discuss the answer to our disks
and tape quiz
tape can only efficiently support
sequential accesses we are reading a
large file from start to end which is a
sequential access so it's okay to use
tape however
the disk will not do too bad on that
either
if however we want to read just the
first and last byte of a large file
for tape we pretty much have to fast
forward through the entire file on tape
so tape is not going to do too well
whereas on disk we will seek to where
the first
and then where the last byte is and just
read it so this will still work
reasonably well here because the disk is
a so-called random access medium meaning
we give it an address and it kind of
goes there with the tape it takes a lot
longer to get to any single position
because we need to really go past all
the other positions
and finally a cat would much rather play
with a reel of tape
than with a hard drive
and there are thousands of youtube
videos that prove this point cats like
stringy things much more than disky
things especially if the disc things
are enclosed in a metal rectangular box